I know cardio may not be everyone's
favorite thing to do but it's a pretty
important part of Fitness now in today's
world virtual training is really really
big companies like NordicTrack are
pretty much killing it in terms of
offering these virtual training classes
with their workout equipment I've been
using the NordicTrack commercial 1750
for a while now and there's a lot to
talk about with this Beast of a
treadmill
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I have the NordicTrack commercial
1750 info review in this video I'm going
to tell you everything there is a note
about this treadmill from the price the
features some pros and some of the cons
and of course who should or maybe should
not buy one of these but before I get
going with all that we've reviewed a lot
of treadmills on barbin.com so if you
want to browse our best list just go
ahead and search barbin best treadmills
and you can find out for yourself which
ones that we like the best
foreign
first of all I really like the fact that
you do have that touch screen monitor
it's a 14 inch display it rotates 360
degrees but it's also going to tilt back
and forward for whatever is most
comfortable for you but cool thing is
there's tons of workouts loaded onto
this monitor with iFit you know you
could obviously you know do some cardio
on this treadmill but if you have any
strength equipment you can also you know
do some strength training classes do
some yoga you know there's a lot you can
do there's over 16 000 classes to be
exact that you can do you know right
here at your fingertips which is really
cool you have incline and decline
settings so this will decline down to
three percent it's also going to Incline
up to 15 percent you have 12 speed
levels as well and all three of those
things are going to be automatically
adjusted during the middle of your
workout depending on you know what that
specific workout is you have incline
Decline and speed setting buttons on
either side of the monitor but you also
have some buttons underneath that way
you can do some more manual and more
precise adjustments so for example on
either side of the monitor you know it's
going to jump up higher than it will
with the buttons so let's talk about the
incline and decline so if you use the
buttons on the left of the monitor it's
going to jump a full degree every single
time you press one of those buttons but
if you use the manual adjustments
underneath it's actually going to cut
that in half which can be pretty helpful
and the same goes for the speed as well
so let's say you don't want to jump from
three miles per hour to four miles per
hour you can use that manual adjustment
on the bottom and go up by 0.1
increments so that's going to be really
helpful for a lot of people out there
one more thing about speed though before
I move on so the buttons to the right of
the monitor actually pretty cool right
here if you double tap that five it's
actually going to go to 5.5 miles per
hour and that's all the way you know
through all the speed options that are
available you have start and stop
buttons underneath the Monitor and in
between both of those buttons is that
stop key it's a really nice safety
feature you know if the treadmill is
moving too fast you need to hop off of
it for you know whatever reason just
pull that key out and everything's going
to come to a complete stop which is you
know just a nice safety feature right
there you have speakers underneath the
monitor you have a built-in fan you have
two water bottle holders which is really
nice the water bottle might wobble
around a little bit but it's not too bad
you also have Bluetooth capabilities for
your headphones your phone a heart rate
monitor and a Bluetooth speaker which is
really cool and I also really like how
this platform right here with the actual
tread itself is going to fold up because
of the Hydraulics underneath it's going
to be really nice as you go to move it
around your personal space and to move
it back down to its original position
all you have to do is take your foot and
press up against that hydraulic and then
pull down at the same time and it's
basically going to take care of
everything on its own and get back down
to the floor
foreign
okay so let's talk about a few potential
issues you might run into with the 1750
and let's go ahead and talk about space
this treadmill is pretty large you know
I don't necessarily think it's the
biggest treadmill out there on the
market but it's definitely not the
smallest so you know space might be an
issue for some people and you know
finding that right area for it to go in
your home it's also pretty expensive
this is listed right around two thousand
dollars you know if you want a more
basic treadmill you can definitely find
one for cheaper you're gonna receive a
free month of iFit with your purchase
but after that you're gonna have to pay
about 40 bucks a month just to gain
access to the available classes now you
don't have to do that there's you know
manual modes and stuff like that you can
do but I personally think you know
that's pretty essential with this
product right here you also have to have
a really strong Wi-Fi connection now I'm
in a garage you know I'm not right up
next to my Wi-Fi router so sometimes
things load a little bit slow for me but
that's also because like I said there's
000 plus workouts loaded on to this
monitor for you to stream so that
definitely is you know playing a factor
in that download speed and just overall
you know quickness of everything as well
now because of the size this is
obviously a pretty heavy treadmill so
thankfully there are some Wheels located
underneath it's going to help you move
this around your home a little bit but I
gotta say they're in kind of a weird
spot and so honestly if you know if you
were to take anything from this I would
probably suggest you keeping it in one
spot and not really trying to move it
around because it's definitely not the
easiest thing in the world and you know
if you take a quick glance at the
monitor right here you'll notice there's
a camera on top some of you might get
excited when you first see that thinking
you're going to have you know some
virtual coaching you can sign up for but
I was a little bit disappointed that the
camera doesn't really serve any purpose
right now now I'm sure that NordicTrack
you know in the not too distant future
is going to add a feature where that
camera is utilized but as of right now
as I'm shooting this video that camera
doesn't do anything
okay so let's expand on the pricing now
for the NordicTrack commercial 1750.
this treadmill is available for right
around 2 500 bucks which it's definitely
not cheap so if you want to save some
money they do offer a treadmill for
about a thousand dollars and you know if
you have a pretty big budget you could
you know spend some more money on one of
their options that features incline up
to 40 degrees now the grand scheme of
things though I think this is the best
value treadmill that they have available
but you know if you want to save over a
thousand dollars you can get that
cheaper one they offer or you can save
even more money and go find yourself an
even more basic treadmill out there
especially if you don't necessarily care
about you know streaming all the workout
classes and all that stuff now compared
to the rest of the market though it's
actually a pretty solid value
considering you do get all of those
luxury features now similar to the rest
of nordictracks equipment they're going
to allow you to finance this purchase if
you don't want to spend you know two
thousand dollars up front this is going
to be determined you know on your
maintenance plan you go for extended
warranty and all that stuff but if you
were to just go for the you know basic
you know standard version of this
treadmill they're going to give you two
different options you can make monthly
payments of about 50 bucks or so for 39
months or you can pay about 170 bucks
for a year and pay it off
okay so let's talk about the classes
that are loaded onto your monitor now
there's a lot so I can't really talk
about all of them but just want to
highlight it a little bit so you can do
your standard you know treadmill class
you can do it in a studio experience
where you have a personal trainer and
there's people in that room with that
trainer kind of adding some motivation
for you or you know you can do like a
global kind of workout and pick almost
any city in the world to go to and that
trainer is going to be walking or
running with you wherever you are so I
just did a simple you know walking
workout the other day with a trainer and
they were walking me around the city and
it's really cool because I was learning
all about the architectural stuff with
the buildings and the culture and
everything I'm kind of a nerd with stuff
like that so not everybody you know is
going to feel the same way about it as
me I think that's really cool you know
especially during an intense workout
gonna distract you a little bit and make
that time go a lot faster trust me it
definitely does aside from that though
there's a lot of other classes as I said
you know you can do some strength
training classes with some dumbbells use
some yoga you can do some simple
stretching they have Ted Talks available
I mean it's essentially endless with the
opportunities that you have with the
classes that you can join another really
cool thing is that you know I talked
about you don't have to have iFit you
can do your own manual workouts or you
can control the incline the decline the
speed all that stuff but you can also
use Google Maps because they're paired
up with iFit with NordicTrack you can
pick really any city in the world so
we're in Nashville so the other day I
was like you know what I might as well
act as if I'm walking around downtown
Nashville that's exactly what I did I
made my own workout and you know they
use the Google camera like Street camera
you can follow along and go down the
actual streets now it's not perfectly
seamless but it's still a really cool
feature and you know say you're training
for the Boston Marathon or any other
Marathon kind of fill in the blank you
can map out that route
and then you know practice that route so
that way when that time comes around
you're ready to go and then also just
think it's really cool how during your
workout you know everything's going to
be adjusted from the incline the speed
the decline all that's going to be
automatically adjusted and direct
correlation to whatever course you're on
so for example you know I was walking
around downtown Nashville the other day
on this treadmill it's going down a hill
and all of a sudden you know this went
into a two percent Decline and then it
leveled back out and then I had to go
uphill so it's going to be really cool
you know it's going to add some
intensity during the middle of your
workouts
[Music]
okay so let's take a second and talk
about the companion app with iFit this
is a really cool feature in my opinion
not only can you track all of your stats
and your workout history and stuff like
that but let's say you're out of town
let's say you're away from home whatever
the case may be you can pull up any kind
of workout that you want to do directly
from your phone and stream it right then
and there so that's really cool you know
you're not tied down to your equipment
that's just a really nice touch now you
can track all of your workouts you know
over the past week month year years past
you can check everything out you click
on the calendars Tab and it's going to
pull up all your recently completed
workouts the trophies tab you know
that's going to show you any you know
achievements that you challenges that
you may have completed you can also
click on Discover it's going to show you
a bunch more for you to do and you can
just sit there and scroll for hours at a
time honestly and just find all these
different workouts that are you know
literally right there at your fingertips
and that's just really cool
okay so let's talk about some of the
technology that's going to be at your
disposal with the 1750. so starting with
the monitor it's a 14 inch display it is
touch screen which is really nice it's
going to tilt whichever way you want it
to go but it's also going to rotate 360
degrees so let's say you want to do a
stretching glass for example you can
flip that monitor around you can set on
the other side of your treadmill and you
can follow along with that clasp so
that's pretty cool the wattage for the
speakers is not listed online but they
honestly sound pretty solid to me they
definitely get the job done there's a
lot of music loaded onto the Monitor and
it's you know actual up-to-date current
music so that's pretty cool and also
really like the automatic adjustments
with the incline Decline and the speed
that's really helpful you know
especially you know as you're following
along with whatever course you know
whatever City you're in it's going to
follow along with the actual Road you're
on so that's just a really cool feature
right there you also have Bluetooth
capabilities for your headphones you
know Bluetooth speaker heart rate
monitor you you know you can kind of you
name it it's going to pair up with your
treadmill and that's a really cool
feature as well and I really really like
the integration with Google Maps you
know like I said if you're planning on
running in a marathon you can map out
that marathon on your monitor right here
and practice and be ready to go for when
the day comes where you're actually
competing in that Marathon now don't get
me wrong you know the belt right here
definitely makes some noise you know it
is a treadmill you're gonna hear it but
it's not like it's the loudest treadmill
in the world so that's really going to
come in handy for any of my early risers
who like working out or maybe even if
you like working out late at night
[Music]
okay so let's break down the build now
and some of the features with the 1750.
there's definitely more plastic than
steel used right here with the framework
but I mean that's pretty common with the
treadmill right and I don't really think
that's you know any reason to turn away
from this treadmill still really nice
quality in terms of your Dimensions this
treadmill is about 80 inches long around
38 inches wide and about 65 inches tall
so it's definitely big you know to say
the least you do have a set of wheels
you have two sets of Wheels actually
underneath this treadmill and that
definitely helps in terms of you know
making it portable moving it around your
personal space but they're not really in
the best spot they could be in so it can
definitely be a little bit tough to move
it around this treadmill weighs about
350 pounds so those wheels are
definitely going to come in handy and it
also has a max weight capacity of 300
pounds that's a pretty solid number
right there itself you have two plastic
cup holders that are big enough to fit
almost any water bottle that you could
have and you do have a 10 year warranty
on the framework of this treadmill which
is you know it's a really nice warranty
right there now you do have that 14 inch
touchscreen display it's gonna be really
nice you know I really like how it
rotates and tilts you know it's a little
variety right there I really think those
automatic adjustments are going to be
super helpful for a lot of people but
also like how you have you know your own
manual adjustments you can make on
either side of the monitor as well as
underneath it I really like those ones
underneath because you know it's not
going to jump up as fast as it will with
the buttons on either side of the
monitor so it's a nice added variety
right there and we cannot forget about
that built-in fan you know you have your
own manual adjustments you can make as
well for that fan speed and the volume
as well you know you can adjust the
volume level of the music your
instructor your overall volume that's
all on the touch screen but you also
have those you know overall button
adjustments for the volume underneath
that monitor foreign
break this down up close and just kind
of show you how everything functions so
I want to talk about these wheels first
yes they're here but they're kind of in
a weird spot now there's a set of wheels
right here which doesn't make a whole
lot of sense in my opinion and they're
also down here which you know that
definitely makes more sense but I think
it would be more helpful if the wheels
were located I guess on the back you
know of the treadmill that way you can
like push it instead of having to pull
it to you it can just be a little weird
sometimes now this is really helpful
with the Hydraulics right here
definitely going to help you out in
terms of space you know you can fold
this up and kind of move it around and
you know kind of fit it in the corner of
your room I guess if you wanted to it's
really simple to fold it up you just
lift up right here on this little handle
and it's going to stay upright right
here for you now to move it back down
you just simply put your foot right here
where the indicator is and pull at the
same time
and it's going to come down on itself
and you can let go and it's going to
slowly go down there and just kind of
take care of that for you you could also
give it a little push and help it out a
little bit if you want to
but that's really a simple process and I
think that's a pretty cool feature right
here now I might as well talk about this
actual platform right here you have a
really nice grip right here you know
you're not going to feel as if you're
slipping around a little bit as you're
running and I found that to be
especially true you know as you know you
go up in speed it's going to help you
out in terms of that traction and you
know keeping your foot where it needs to
be so let's transition further up now
you know this little handle right here
as well as these arms is going to be
really nice you know if you get tired
you want to kind of rest your hands but
as you can see there's no type of heart
rate sensor built into this right here
and you know that would be kind of cool
the last Model did in fact have that but
they took that feature away and they
also used to have a tray down here for
you to store some more stuff I'm
personally like not having that but I
think these heart rate sensors right
here would be a really nice touch
especially if you don't have a heart
rate monitor now right here on this
underneath this monitor right here
you'll find all of your manual
adjustments for the incline your speed
start stop is also that stop key right
here you just pull out on it
everything's going to stop immediately
for you so that's really really nice in
terms of safety your fan speed is right
here as well as your overall speed of
the treadmill and these are those two
cup holders I was talking about you know
as you can see they're pretty big and
you can fit the majority of water
bottles it doesn't matter how big it is
in my opinion I think they're going to
fit for the most part except for maybe
like a gallon jug or something all right
now let's transition to this monitor But
first you know you do have your incline
and decline as well as your mile per
hour adjustments right here on either
side I'll talk about that more in just a
second especially that mile per hour so
just hang tight but this is a 14 inch
touchscreen display your speakers are
right here underneath the display as you
can see you know I've got my profile you
can also invite up to four different
people on your iFit membership which is
you know pretty cool you can split that
monthly payment or yearly payment really
however you want to do it you can also
essentially split everything together
including the actual price tag of this
treadmill so that's pretty cool so going
to click on my name right here go ahead
and head to the home page
as you can see you know there's a lot of
classes it's taken a while to load so
actually you know I might as well go
ahead and connect to my hotspot and all
of these settings are going to be right
here on the side I know it's kind of
small and it's kind of hard to see but
we're going to click on Wi-Fi and go
ahead and change our settings I need to
make sure that my Hotspot is turned on
but that doesn't take very long now does
it all right so once this pops up you
know I'm going to go ahead and select my
my phone and get that hotspot rolling
okay so now we're good to go and while
I'm here showing you this menu I might
as well show you the rest of everything
you can do right here now there's a lot
you can do you can switch your profile
you can invite users here your Bluetooth
accessories option is here you can
change your appearance put it in dark
mode or keep it in light mode or you
know vice versa whatever click on my
account right here it's going to show
all your personal stuff you can you know
edit all that and it's going to really
boil down to the type of workouts you
want to do how often you want to work
out often you are active all that good
stuff you can edit all that right there
now if you can see your past seven days
you can change that to you know past 30
days year to date and all that good
stuff as you keep scrolling you'll see
latest from iFit challenges recommended
workouts and series but you can also
Browse by category you know running
walking hiking walk run beginner there's
a lot of different you know options
right there for you you can click on
create or that's calendar excuse me it's
kind of hard to see that's calendar
you're going to see a bunch of different
things right there if it were to load
you're going to see create right here
and this is it pulled up Cape Town South
Africa right there that's really cool to
me you know if you want to explore a
city you've never been to before you
know that's that's pretty cool you can
definitely do so right there and you can
see that street view camera if you want
to and also go to browse
I'm gonna go ahead and exit that right
there we're gonna go to browse and from
here I mean this is really going to pull
up a full library of everything that is
offered and there's filters right here
you can search by the trainer the type
of workout you know if you're going to
be needing any type of equipment you
know all of that and you can see right
here completed stuff as well so I did
one in New York the other day I did one
in Nashville the other day and that's
just really cool all the challenges are
going to be right here again there's
iFit 101 do your studio classes here and
you know walk on the beach in a desert
in the forest there's different
landmarks you can choose from that's
just really cool to me it's going to
really you know cut down on mentally how
long the workout feels and just kind of
distract you a little bit so that's
really cool now you can also go to
trophy case and if you have any type of
challenges you've completed you know
it's all going to pop up right there and
you can also click on Discover
challenges over here to the right and
it's going to pull up you know all the
different types of challenges that you
can do as I said you know it does kind
of take a while to load sometimes I am
on a hot spot but there's a lot right
here for it to load so you know it's
kind of just give it give it some leeway
right here and just be patient I promise
it'll be worth it now if you go back to
home one more thing right here you can
do manual start and I'm actually going
to hop up here now
I want to go ahead and show you guys you
know you can tilt this monitor but let
me stand on either side start moving on
me you can tilt this monitor pretty far
up you know if you're really tall you
know that way you don't have to Crane
your neck too hard and you know just to
stare at the screen this also is going
to rotate 360 degrees so that's really
nice too it doesn't keep going but it
will rotate just like that on the other
side too that way you can stand off the
actual treadmill go over over on the
back and do any other workout now up
here at the top you're going to track
your incline calories burned time
elapsed your distance your speed all of
that and it's going to be able to it
would work for me it's going to show you
all this other stuff to all these other
stats
but we're gonna go in in the warm-up and
get right into it as you can see it has
a quarter mile track length right here
and honestly you can just go ahead and
get on it and just get straight to your
workout now I talked about how you do
have these manual adjustments down here
that's gonna be really helpful you know
you can obviously click incline
and we're going to start inclining right
here
as you can see that go up for me
but if you don't want to do it that slow
you know those are pretty pretty small
increments pretty small adjustments
let's say you want to go you know
straight to a 10 well you can press that
10 up here and it's going to go ahead
and do all of that for you all right so
whenever you're in the middle of your
workout your manual one specifically you
know you can adjust the incline let's
talk about that if you press this button
right here it'll show you on the screen
it's going to go up in 0.5 percent every
single time or you can press you know
one of these buttons I'm going to press
15 and it's going to go all the way up
to that 15 degree grade which is really
cool it's kind of just you can do it on
its own and that's really easy and the
same goes for the speed so here let me
go ahead and bring this
go ahead and bring this back down to
zero once it's done
go and bring it right back down it's
really seamless it does it at a pretty
quick rate you can also change your
speed right here with this manual
adjustment that's going to go in 0.1
increments but
if you want to go ahead let's go ahead
and move it up to three
so then go ahead kicks in right away on
its own another cool thing is you can
double tap that three
and it goes to 3.3 miles per hour which
is a really cool feature same thing goes
for 5.5
and go ahead and go right there and then
you can go ahead and increase it more if
you want go ahead and press that 10. and
you can really get going but we want to
go ahead and bring it on back down
just like that and go and bring it right
back down to zero
now we're cruising again one cool one
thing that would be cool to have excuse
me would be this camera actually serving
some type of Purpose with a personal
trainer for example when you kind of
interact as of right now that's not a
feature but I really would not be
surprised if NordicTrack adds that in
the not too distant future a couple more
things here right here I'm going to
press stop
come to a complete stop right here you
can end your workout at the end you know
it's going to show you your workout
stats mine wasn't very long right then
it's just for the purpose of this video
but you know it's going to break down
every single thing and a distance
calorie burn and it's going to show like
The Fast Max Speed you were on the max
incline you're on do the same thing with
decline if I would have done it right
then and if you're in any type of class
it's also going to have a leaderboard
based off of your personal stats that
you had right then and there now one
last thing though
you do need a three-prong Outlet to
power this treadmill the cord's pretty
long though which is really nice but you
do have a power switch located on the
back up here on the front technically
and it's really recommended that you you
know flip that switch to off and then
unplug your treadmill every time you're
done using it that way you can avoid any
type of potential power surge and then
everything's fried you definitely don't
want that
okay so let's talk about the people who
might want to purchase this treadmill
well anyone looking for a treadmill with
tons of classes available at their
fingertips ding ding ding I think you
found your winner right here if you're
looking for a high-tech treadmill that
has a lot of features I think you also
want to take a hard look at this one
right here because there's a lot you
know especially those automatic
adjustments plus you can create your own
custom workouts literally anywhere in
the world so if you want to spend the
afternoon in Egypt you know maybe in
Alaska you know maybe over in London you
know wherever it is in the world you can
do it which is really cool
and when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase the 1750 in my opinion
it really just boils down to three
different things let's talk about the
money first if you don't want to spend
two grand on a treadmill you know you
definitely don't have to you can find
some cheaper ones out there you know
this is a luxury item though and that's
why you're paying that luxury price tag
and you know let's say you don't care
about streaming your your workout
classes no you don't have to do so you
don't have to sign up for iFit but you
know that's how this treadmill was
intended to be used and if you're not
going to use that I definitely suggest
saving your money on a more basic
treadmill and lastly is the space you
know a treadmill is a treadmill it's
going to take up a good amount of space
regardless of the brand you know the
model the make you know whatever it may
be it's going to dominate a good amount
of space that's especially true with the
1750 though so you know some of you may
just simply not have enough space for
this to be added to your home that's all
she wrote for today's review over the
NordicTrack commercial 1750. I've been
really impressed with this treadmill I
really like the automatic adjustments
also really enjoy the inclusion of iFit
because I'm really never going to run
out of workouts to do it is pretty
expensive it's also pretty big and it
can be a little bit difficult to move
around at certain times but you know if
you do have the budget for it and the
space for it I think you're going to be
pretty pumped with this purchase thanks
for watching everybody I hope this video
was really helpful and that I was able
to tell you everything that you need to
know about this treadmill as always stay
tuned for my next video but for now I
think you should definitely head over to
barbin.com to read more about this
awesome product all you got to do is
search bar Bend NordicTrack commercial
1750 treadmill review and you'll find
all the details of everything that we
talked about here today I'll catch y'all
next time
[Music]